Guide to the Joanne Temcov Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Joanne Temcov papers
1969-2018
1969-1990
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6040
6040-001
Temcov, Joanne L.$q(Joanne Little)
2.75 cubic feet (4 boxes)
Papers relating to Joanne Temcov's work as a labor organizer and women’s rights advocate
Joanne Little Temcov (1926-) is a labor organizer and women’s rights advocate. She was born in Montesano, Washington and studied drama at the University of Washington. In the 1960s and 1970s she worked in various roles: Interviewer, Washington State Employment Security Department; Secretary and then President, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) Local 435; Executive Board member, Washington Federation of State Employees (WFSE); and Industrial Relations Agent, Washington State Department of Labor and Industries. In the 1970s and 1980s Temcov was an active member of the National Organization for Women (NOW), the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), and the Women's Political Caucus. She also served as the secretary of the Pacific Northwest Labor History Association (PNLHA).
This collection is organized into three series:
SERIES 1: LABOR UNION ACTIVITIES FILES, 1969-1990, 2018
SERIES 2: WOMEN’S RIGHTS SUBJECT FILES, 1970-1998
SERIES 3: PACIFIC NORTHWEST LABOR HISTORY ASSOCIATION FILES, 1970-2015
Materials are related to Temcov's labor union activities and women's rights advocacy work, including correspondence, reports, resolutions, meeting minutes, press releases, memos, agendas, convention proceedings, newsletters, speeches, essays, photographs, pamphlets, booklets, brochures, fliers, programs, biographical narratives, notes, and newspaper articles. Also included are materials relating to the early years of the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW); the activities of the Seattle-King County and Snohomish County chapters of the National Organization for Women (NOW); and the national, Washington State, King County, and Snohomish County Women's Political Caucus.
Materials include conference programs, meeting minutes, memos, correspondence, fliers, brochures, essays, photographs, programs, song sheets, and newspaper clippings about the Pacific Northwest Labor History Association (PNLHA).
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Open to all users, but some materials in this collection exist in a format that is inaccessible to researchers. Production of use copies is required before access will be granted; this may delay research requests. Advanced notice is required.
Materials donated by Joanne Temcov 2016-10-25, 2018-01-25, 2018-07-05, and 2018-10-07.
Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington),; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Women
- LABOR UNION ACTIVITIES FILES, 1969-1990, 2018; 1969-1990; SERIES 1; 1.6 cubic feet (2 shared boxes)
  Materials include correspondence, reports, resolutions, press releases, memos, agendas, convention proceedings, programs, biographical narratives, notes, and newspaper articles relating to Temcov’s labor union activities with Washington Federation of State Employees (WFSE) Council 28, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) Local 435, the Washington State Labor Council (WSLC), and the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW). in WFSE, Temcov served on WFSE's Policy Committee and Executive Committee as well.
  - Joanne Temcov's biography, 2018 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - AFL-CIO: resolutions, pamphlets, booklets about women workers and other labor issues, 1970s (Box-folder 1/17)
  - MANPOWER: list of reports about employment, 1971 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - United Farm Workers of America: press release, approximately 1970-1980 (Box-folder 1/32)
  - International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (IAM): report about political engagement and newsletter, 1972 (Box-folder 1/33)
  - United Workers Union: newsletter, 1974 (Box-folder 1/34)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union: flier and brochures about union activities, approximately 1970-1980 (Box-folder 1/35)
  - Committee for National Health Insurance: press release and brochure, 1975 (Box-folder 1/36)
  - Coalition to Stop Inflation: correspondence, 1980s (Box-folder 1/40)
  - Newspaper articles about labor issues, 1970s (Box-folder 1/43)
  - Retirement reform: memos, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Retirement reform: notes, brochures, and handbook, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Retirement reform: correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Retirement reform: newsletters and newspaper clippings, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Retirement reform: WFSE legislative reports, WA Senate Bill no. 500, and WA House Bill no. 435, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Retirement reform: reports, draft resolutions, agenda, and statistics, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - WSLC: draft resolutions, pension gender equity resolution, and list of affiliates, 1974 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - WFSE Council 28: convention agenda, resolutions and constitutional amendments, and amended resolutions, 1976 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - WSLC: pamphlets, brochures, flier, Labor and Industries Industrial Welfare Order on working conditions for women and minors, 1972 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - WSLC: committee lists, agenda, newsletters, "labor summer school" pamphlet, and fliers, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - WFSE Council 28: organizational charts, convention agenda, convention resolutions and amendments, reports, newsletters, notes, and a photograph, 1971 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - WFSE Council 28: resolutions, amendments, memos, agenda, certificate, and newsletters, 1972 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - WFSE Council 28: resolutions, constitution and bylaws, agenda, memos, minutes, and membership statistics, 1973 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - WFSE Council 28: convention packet, resolutions, and amendments, 1974 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - AFSCME Local 435 and WFSE Council 28: memos, correspondence, notes, and reports about employment security grievances, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Union convention name tags and pins and union membership cards, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - WFSE and WSLC: narratives about Temcov's union work, convention resolutions and amendments, agenda, brochures, and bound WSLC proceedings, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - WFSE and WSLC: narratives about Temcov's union work, convention resolutions and amendments, agenda, brochures, and bound WSLC proceedings, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - COALITION OF LABOR UNION WOMEN (CLUW) FILES, 1974-2011; Subseries 1.A.; 0.16 cubic feet (1 shared box)
    Materials include memos, meeting minutes, correspondence, resolutions, newsletters, brochures, programs, notes, and newspaper articles relating to Temcov’s work with the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW).
    - CLUW: background information, brochures, and leaflets, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - CLUW: newsletters, 1990s, undated (Box-folder ½)
    - CLUW: directory and mailing lists, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - CLUW: memos, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - CLUW: meeting minutes and programs, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - CLUW: correspondence, 1974-1989 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - CLUW: project plans, 1988 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - CLUW: founding conference programs, notes, and resolutions, 1974 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - CLUW: presentations, 1976 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - CLUW: constitution, 1975 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - CLUW: newspaper articles, 1974-2011 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - CLUW: buttons and a sticker, approximately 1970-1980 (Box-folder 1/12)
- WOMEN’S RIGHTS SUBJECT FILES, 1970-2008; 1970-1989; SERIES 2; 1.15 cubic feet (2 boxes, 1 shared box)
  Materials are related to Temcov's women's rights advocacy work, including correspondence, reports, resolutions, meeting minutes, press releases, memos, newsletters, speeches, essays, presentation slides, pamphlets, booklets, brochures, fliers, programs, notes, and newspaper articles. Also included are materials relating to the activities of the Seattle-King County and Snohomish County chapters of the National Organization for Women (NOW) and the national, Washington State, King County, and Snohomish County Women's Political Caucus.
  Access note: Open to all users, but some materials in this series exist in a format that is inaccessible to researchers. Production of use copies is required before access will be granted; this may delay research requests. Advanced notice is required.
  - Comparable Worth Task Force, Washington State: research and reports, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Comparable Worth Task Force, Washington State: workshop presentation and brochures, 1987 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Gender income inequality presentation slides, class materials, and charts, 1970-1990; 1 DVD-R (Box-folder 1/15)
    Access restricted: production of use copy is required before access will be granted
  - U.S. Department of Labor and Industry: press releases, pamphlets, and booklets about women workers, 1970s (Box-folder 1/16)
  - United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW): program and report about women workers, 1970 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Know Inc.: press release about women workers, 1972 (Box-folder ½0)
  - University of Washington YWCA: bibliography, 1970 (Box-folder ½1)
  - Harding, Nina "The interconnections between the Black struggle and the woman question" essay presented at Seattle Radical Women annual conference, 1970 (Box-folder ½2)
  - Progressive Women: press release about National Organization for Women (NOW), 1971 (Box-folder ½3)
  - Women's Heritage Series Inc.: newsletters, 1972 (Box-folder ½4)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW): press release, 1970 (Box-folder ½5)
  - Women's Liberation School: class schedule, 1971 (Box-folder ½6)
  - Everywoman Bookstore: catalog, 1971 (Box-folder ½7)
  - Cisler, Lucinda, "Women: A Bibliography" booklet, 1970 (Box-folder ½8)
  - American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME): report, memo, and questionnaires about women workers, 1973-1974 (Box-folder ½9)
  - San Francisco Board of Supervisors: resolution about equal rights for women in the workplace, 1971 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - W.A.G.E.: newsletters, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - National Lawyers Guild: brochure about Yvonne Wanrow Defense Committee, 1975 (Box-folder 1/37)
  - The Leagues of Women Voters in King County, Washington: brochures, 1977 (Box-folder 1/41)
  - National Council of Women’s Organizations: newsletter, 1998 (Box-folder 1/42)
  - Women's rights: newspaper articles, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - NATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR WOMEN (NOW) FILES, 1970-1989; Subseries 2.A.; 0.46 cubic feet (1 box)
    Materials include meeting minutes, resolutions, memos, reports, speeches, essays, agendas, newsletters, pamphlets, brochures, and newspaper articles relating to the activities of the Seattle-King County and Snohomish County chapters of the National Organization for Women (NOW).
    - National Organization for Women (NOW) national conference: resolutions, speeches, essays, agenda, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), Seattle-King County chapter: newsletter and member list, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), Seattle-King County chapter: meeting minutes and draft newsletters, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Women's rights: NOW newsletters, memos, and resolutions; newspaper articles; pamphlets; and brochures, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), Snohomish chapter: newsletters and memos, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), Seattle-King County chapter, Speakers Bureau: bulletins, member lists, resolutions, speeches, notes, reports, and memos, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), Washington: memos, press releases, resolutions, newsletters, and newspaper articles, approximately 1970-1985 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW): newsletters, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), Snohomish chapter: correspondence, memos, newsletters, and newspaper articles, 1972 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - WOMEN'S POLITICAL CAUCUS FILES, 1971-2008; Subseries 2.B.; 0.37 cubic feet (1 box)
    Materials include meeting minutes, memos, reports, agendas, correspondence, membership rosters, brochures, financial records, newsletters, and newspaper articles relating to the activities of the national, Washington State, King County, and Snohomish County Women's Political Caucus.
    - National, Washington State, and King County Women's Political Caucus: reports, meeting minutes, newsletters, letters to the editor, newspaper clippings, promotional materials, and pamphlets, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 4/1-2)
    - King County and Washington State Women's Political Caucus: correspondence, meeting minutes, agenda, caucus reports, membership roster (Washington State), newsletters, newspaper clippings, contact sheet, and fact sheets, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - National Women's Political Caucus board meeting hosted by Washington State Women's Political Caucus: agenda, correspondence, schedules, brochures, and financial records, 1979 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - King County and Washington State Women's Political Caucus: bylaws, meeting minutes, correspondence, newsletters, agenda, membership rosters (King County), budgets, policy documents, fliers, fact sheets, convention planning documents, and notes, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Snohomish County Women's Political Caucus: bylaws, meeting minutes, correspondence, agenda, membership rosters, Temcov's account of her experiences in the branch, brochures, and newspaper articles, 1983 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Snohomish County Women's Political Caucus: meeting minutes, correspondence, and newspaper articles, 1983 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - National Women's Political Caucus board meeting hosted in Seattle, WA: correspondence, notes, meeting minutes, receipts, and hotel information, 1988 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - King County and Washington State Women's Political Caucus: newsletters, bylaws amendments, bylaws (Washington State), agenda, budget report, and fliers, 1990-2008 (Box-folder 4/9)
- PACIFIC NORTHWEST LABOR HISTORY ASSOCIATION FILES, 1970-2015; 1980-1995; SERIES 3; 0.16 cubic feet (4 files)
  Materials include conference programs, meeting minutes, memos, correspondence, fliers, brochures, essays, photographs, programs, song sheets, and newspaper clippings about the Pacific Northwest Labor History Association (PNLHA).
  - Pacific Northwest Labor History Association: brochure, 1981 (Box-folder 1/38)
  - Southwest Labor Studies Conference: program, 1990 (Box-folder 1/39)
  - Pacific Northwest Labor History Association: constitution, bylaws, meeting minutes, memos, membership lists, and correspondence, 1977-1995 (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Pacific Northwest Labor History Association: conference programs, meeting minutes, fliers, brochures, essays, photographs, song sheets, and newspaper clippings, 1970-2015 (Box-folder 2/21)